Byron Sorgdrager

Address: London

Mobile: +44 78 2831 6872 Email: byron-cv@company6.co.uk

Professional Profile

Highly motivated, dedicated and accomplished IT professional armed with over twenty years of experience and outstanding set of skills and credentials. Regarded for unquestionable drive to succeed and continuous pursuit for excellence and professionalism even in the most challenging circumstances and situations. Possesses excellent communication skills gained through variety of client facing roles, complemented by ability to quickly build rapport and understand customer requirements, subsequently allowing meeting and exceeding customer expectations and delivering highest quality results. Recognised as a hands-on team leader with solid understanding of complexities within IT and project management, strategic planning abilities and unquestionable commercial acumen.

Key Skills

- **Communication and Interpersonal Skills** Possesses exceptional communication skills and relationship management capabilities complemented by outstanding ability to convey complex information in a clear and understandable manner.
- Analytical & Problem Solving Skills Demonstrates solid ability to address and tackle a wide array of technical issues in a logical and rational way, using creativity, innovation and judgement to find the perfect solution.
- **Teamwork & Leadership** Recognised as natural leader, capable of maintaining team spirit, effectively leading, motivating and developing teams to consistently deliver excellent performance, with particular focus on client satisfaction.
- **Organisational & Planning** Highly skilled in multitasking and prioritising assigned tasks from start to their successful completion within strict deadlines and to a high standard.
- **Security by Design** Skilled and experienced at ensuring precision and correctness of the information handled and communicated in secure and trusted ways. Filled in for various SA/CSO positions.
- **Project Management & Industry knowledge** Adept in all facets of running projects in a quick-paced commercial environment with track record of consistently delivering outstanding results within time and budgetary constrains.
- Technical Competencies Highly competent and experienced in using variety of IT solutions to deliver commercial benefits Linux RedHat, CentOS, SuSe, Slackware, Debian, Ubuntu; Microsoft Windows (All flavours from 3.x onward; Network Devices Cisco, HP, Accent, F5; Process; Policies; Procedure Agile, ITIL, COBIT, RFC, ISO17799, ISO27001, GDPR; Virtualization Cloud (Azure, AWS, Google Cloud, GCP, EC2, Verizon, GCloud, OpenNebula, OpenStack), Xen, VMWare, VDI, KVM; Tools Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, VSTS, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana (ELK), Vault, SSL / TLS, RPM builds, Active Directory, AD, LDAP, BASH, PHP, MySQL, NoSQL, SAP, Akamai, SVN, GIT, BitBucket, Docker, Consul, Kubernetes, Splunk, SonarQube, JFrog; Collaboration Slack, HipChat, Confluence, JIRA; Monitoring OpsView (Nagios), ZenOSS, NewRelic.

Additional Information

Achievement highlights

- Designed, built and grew a team to expand on online court services for Her Majesty's Courts and Tribunal Services, allowing the Ministry of Justice to modernise services such as Probate, Divorce, Child Services, Money Claims and more. Facilitated from PoC up to Public Beta and Live.
- Created, designed and implemented first pharmaceutical benefits management system in Africa decreasing average turnaround time for medical aid (pharmacy input to payment) from 4 weeks to under 2 minutes.
- Created, developed and implemented virtual ISP system to manage all facets of non-Tier 1 ISP services reducing time; procurement to provisioning from three days to five minutes.
- Drafted policy and facilitated IPv6 peering for ISPA internet exchanges in Africa.
- Secured and implemented "self-service" portal for Inland Revenue and Customs.

Professional Experience

Sept 2018 – Present Backend (Infrastructure) Engineer Bó (NatWest/RBS)

- Hands-on role; Responsible for securing, stabilising, architecting and maintaining the public cloud infrastructure for a companion bank
- Automate backend banking infrastructure. Jenkins, Terraform, AWS, Splunk, LDAP, Kubernetes, Docker,
 Packer, Vault, IAM roles, Git, CloudWatch, S3
- Security architecture and process. Encryption at rest/transit. PII protection. Security Incident investigations and response.

April 2018 – July 2018 Senior Consultant

HM Ministry of Justice (HMCTS)

 Consultation to facilitate identify and access management migration in Azure. LDAP, IDAM, Terraform, Ansible, SAML, SSO, PaaS, Vault, KeyStore, SSL, TLS, Linux, CentOS, RHEL, ELK

Nov 2016 – Feb 2018 Lead Platform / DevOps Engineer HM Ministry of Justice (HMCTS)

- Hands-on role; Responsible for the creation, automation, expansion and integration of an Azure platform using Linux/Windows for central government as client.
- Automation, continuous integration, security and platform expansion of cloud environments (Azure); Vendor/supplier interaction (IaaS/PaaS). Infrastructure support. Focus on Data Protection.
- Solution design for integration with wider projects; Focus on security as core requirement.
- Security consultation to protect PII (threat to life). Designed and implemented security platform and facilitated surrounding processes.
- Senior Management influence regarding data governance/security and release/transition management.
- Technologies actively used: Ansible, Jenkins, GitHub Enterprise, Linux (RedHat RHEL/CentOS), Microsoft Azure (CentOS, RHEL), Logstash, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Apache, NginX, Docker, TLS, SSL, VPN (IPSec), Jira/Confluence, pfSense, F5, Terraform, Microsoft Azure PaaS/laaS, OpenVPN. Set up Kubernetes cluster.

July 2016 – Oct 2016 DevOps Engineer / Consultant PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC)

- Hands-on role; Responsible for the automation and integration of an in-house built platform using the LAMP/ELK stack for local government as client.
- Daily tasks include automation, continuous integration, security and platform expansion of into cloud environments (Azure); Vendor/supplier interaction.
- Technologies actively used: Ansible (Galaxy), Jenkins, Git, Linux (RedHat RHEL/CentOS), Microsoft Azure (Openlogic CentOS, RHEL), New Relic, Hashicorp products (Terraform, Consul, Vault), Logstash, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Apache, NginX, Vagrant, Docker, TLS, SSL, VPN (IPSec), J2EE, MongoDB, Stash/Jira/Confluence.

June 2015 – June 2016 IT Platforms Management

British Broadcasting Corp (BBC)

- Responsible for all aspects of the IT platform inside the Research and Development department. This includes but is not limited to 100Gb network links, security, policies, first-line up to third-line support, remote access and any project work dependant on IT infrastructure or platform.
- Hands-on and managerial role; However, accountable for managing personnel issues related to system administration team.
- Responsible for all aspects of design and implementation of: Datacentre refresh aimed at redundancy;
 Design and implementation of up-scaled virtual cloud environment; Windows estate (AD) upgrade; Core
 Cisco network upgrade; Telephony upgrade; Implemented new media streaming service; Video conferencing replacement and integration; Replacement of backup solution; Disaster Recovery and Security Incident procedures.
- Daily tasks included monitoring, upgrading and servicing research and development needs on the platform.
- Cisco, Iptables, Linux, Windows, LDAP, VPN, OE, Docker, OpenStack, AWS, CI (Jenkins), Puppet, SDI, Symantec, VMWare, CA (Internal TLS/SSL), PKI, OTP, Nagios, J2EE, Tomcat, Git, PHP, Nginx, BASH.
- Directed and vision mixed AllStaff Productions. Included technical setup.

June 2014 - May 2015 Senior Technical Consultant

Phorm Inc.

- Re-hired to assist rapid business expansion, entrusted to lead highly challenging and demanding projects implementing and improving IT solutions, troubleshooting, escalations and break-fix solutions, and providing comprehensive training to staff.
- Responsible for all aspects of design and implementation of networks, security and operational solutions pfSense, Cisco, Iptables and Linux RedHat/CentOS 5.x-6.x-7.x hardening; implementation and automation of core advertising products RPM builds, PHP, BASH, DHCP, BOOTP, Kickstart, LDAP, DNS, SSH, Apache, Akamai, LDAP, SVN, LAMP, EC2; and data management Hadoop/HBase/MongoDB.

Feb 2014 - May 2014 Technical Architect

HM Insolvency Service

- Selected to lead virtualisation of existing systems and datacentre relocation for organisation operating from 35 different sites with over 2,000 users across the UK.
- Responsible for all aspects of migrating existing applications from physical to virtual infrastructures (VMWare), migrating SAP data services and business objects, whilst ensuring BAU and business logic are not detrimentally affected, and relocating datacentre, managing all relevant and required documentation, plans and their execution, network and security equipment (IP/DNS/Cisco/Juniper/Windows) and creating iRules (F5) in line with business continuity plans.
- Secured data migration via PSN and introduced encryption in transit methods to facilitate integrated transport of data.

Feb 2014 - Feb 2014 Senior Consultant

HM Ministry of Justice

 Short consultation on security solution design and architecture for authentication / authorization.

Oct 2013 - Jan 2014 IT/Automation Consultant

SABMiller Plc

- Designed and built automated information web portal, encompassing quality assurance, business intelligence and invoicing, for worlds second largest brewing company, operating in 75 countries.
- Utilised knowledge and skills in using SAP/Hana, MySQL, PHP and Linux to successfully and effectively lead and complete the project.

Mar 2013 - Sep 2013 Senior Infrastructure Engineer

- **Goldmoney Ltd**
- Responsible for managing integrity and maintenance of the infrastructure, re-designing infrastructure, and security, and handling outages and queries from various internal business units.
- Used expert knowledge and skills in utilising Linux, Cisco, Apache, RPM Builds, PHP, MySQL, .NET, Microsoft, NetApp, Nagios, Akamai, SVN, Bamboo, Puppet, JIRA, Confluence, Crowd, LVS, Zend, AWS, LDAP, Ruby, virtualization and cloud, Cisco, IPTables and Akamai, to successfully perform key duties and responsibilities.

Mar 2012 - Feb 2013 IT Services Manager

Queen Mary University of London

- Responsible for all aspects of daily management of IT infrastructure supporting university operations and functions, ensuring any arising IT issues do not detrimentally affect the work of staff or students.
 Overlooking adherence to set procedures, providing support within agreed SLAs, incident and problem management within ITIL and handling any arising escalations.
- Accountable for managing all personnel issues related to system administration team recruitment, HR issues, performance and reviews.

Oct 2011 - Feb 2012 IT Consultant/ System Administrator Fresh Media Group/Ceros

Played key role in delivering effective implementations and ensuring operational integrity on numerous projects - design and implementation of core services (Linux, Apache, RPM Builds, PHP, SWF, PDF, MySQL, NFS, Ruby), migration of core services to a visualized environment (Verizon Cloud, HAProxy), Automation and integration of core products and systems (BASH, PHP), development of automated release platform (Git, SVN, LDAP, Mercurial, BASH, RPM, Puppet, Rsync, VDI VirtualBox), design and implementation of automated monitoring and escalation (Opsview) and design and implementation of security and failover (OpenVPN, IPTables, Cloud).

Mar 2007 – Sep 2011 Global NOC Team Lead

Phorm Inc.

- Primary function was the design and deployment of secure integrated solutions for ISPs including the
 daily operational management of support team and systems. Designed and implemented centralized
 configuration management system and "single-server" solution. Interfaced with various ISPs in pre-sales
 and pre-launch environments. Third-line support for major incidents and security breaches.
- Promoted from System Administrator to Senior System Administrator. Promoted from Senior System Administrator to Global NOC Team Leader. Multiple contract extensions.
- Technologies include SVN, LDAP, BASH, RPM, Puppet, Rsync, PHP, MySQL, NoSQL, OpsView, Nagios, F5,
 IPTables, Cisco, Linux, CentOS, RedHat, AWS, Akamai, JIRA, Confluence, BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, SCRUM, Kernel optimasation, UltraDNS, GeoIP DNS/LDAP, Automated builds, CI, Jenkins, BOOTP, PXE, Kickstart, NFS, ITIL

Previous Employment

Jul 2006 - Feb 2007	Solutions Architect	JR Investments
Feb 2006 - Jun 2006	Senior Systems Engineer	Systems Fusion
May 2005 - Jan 2006	Information Security Specialist	South African Revenue Service
Jan 2004 - Jan 2005	Systems Engineer	Telkom SA
Nov 2001 - Dec 2003	Consultant	Organising Enterprises and Labour
Dec 1999 - Oct 2001	Systems Engineer	Posix Systems
May 1996 - Nov 1999	Systems Engineer	Mediscor Ltd
Apr 1995 - Apr 1996	Computer Engineer	Canon Western Transvaal
Dec 1993 – Mar 1995	Computer Engineer	The Computer Shop

Education and Professional Development

2010	ITIL v3 Foundations	APM Group
2006	SUN Identity Manager	Sun Microsystems
2005	CISCO PIX Advanced	Torque IT
2000	Certified Linux Administrator	Brainbench
2000	Certified Unix Administrator	Brainbench
2000	Cisco ISP (Multi-Home) Routing Design	Cisco
1998	WebSpeed Programming Certification	Progress
1995	Novell Netware v4 Administrator	Novell